





Last Active: Oct-Dec 2020 Last Modified: Oct-Dec 2020

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Accomplished software professional with overall 14+ years of experience in wireless audio Bluetooth, multimedia frameworks and embedded systems. Proven abilities in software development, managing projects, problem solving, analyzing and good debugging skills. Very good in customer interaction and thus helped employer in competitive advantages.

Work Experience

- Mindtree as Technical Manager Jan 2021 to Till Date
- Broadcom as Senior Software Engineer Feb 2013 to Jan 2021

Working knowledge of profiles like A2DP, HFP, SPP and protocols like RFCOMM, L2CAP, AVDTP. Bluetooth transports like SDIO, H4-UART

Linux drivers - V4L2 based drivers, SDIO drivers.

Worked on codec integration like AAC, APT-X, MP3.on android platforms.

Good knowledge of audio frameworks and hardware interfaces.

Good debugging skills using analyzers.

Nowon Technologies as Technical Leader

Jun 2010 to Feb 2013

Worked on Integration of media codecs, file parser, hardware/software codecs to android frame work. Performance optimization in opencore.

Aricent Holdings Pvt Ltd as Technical Leader

Apr 2005 to Jun 2010

Worked on Integration of media codecs, file parser, hardware/software codecs to android frame work. Worked with Mcrosoft's Digital Rights Management (DRM) technology. Mcrosoft's Media Transfer Protocol (MTP).

Dshow Domain knowledge and Transform Filters/DMO development in Direct Show.

• Accel Frontline Services Ltd. as Embedded Software Engineer Mar 2003 to Jun 2005

Projects involving interfacing with LED, LCD, DAC and EEPROM modules. Uses I2C and RS485 interfaces between modules. Design and implementation and Firmware Development for interfacing LCD, LED and I2C.

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (ECE) from Calicut University in 2000

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Bluetooth	2020
C, C++	2020
Multimedia	2020
EMBEDDED systems	2020
Android SDK	2018
Linux, Windows	2020
MACHINE LEARNING	0 0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓	
Malayalam	Expert	✓	✓	✓	

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.